Contact

Av. De Roma n. 47 6 dto, Lisboa 1700 Portugal +351933815239 (Mobile) afonsoscunha@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/afonsocunha-3ab6311 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hotel Management Resorts Hotels

Languages

English French Spanish

Afonso Cunha

General Manager at Vilalara Thalassa and Spa Resort Lisbon Area, Portugal

Summary

Working for Four Seasons for over 15 years has taken me to city hotels of Europe and Asia and onto resorts in North America, Hawaii and now Canada. Personal, innovative and anticipatory service is what I consistently strive for.My time with Four Seasons has given me the opportunity to combine my operations knowledge and leadership skills to constantly increase the employee and guest experience.Having worked in such distinct environments made me an expert on world traveler expectations and different work force environments

Some of my specialties include Hotel opening experience, strategic planning, operations and focus on customer satisfaction, people succession planning, motivating and mentoring. training, coaching. Also worked in a Union environment

Experience

Vilalara Thalassa Spa Resort General Manager April 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month) Faro Area, Portugal

Responsible for the day-to-day management of a flagship and very luxurious resort and its staff. I am Accountable for planning, organizing, and directing all hotel services, including front-of-house (reception, concierge, and reservation) services, food and beverage operations,, housekeeping. guest services, accounting,, marketing, recreation and the maintenance/grounds and landscaping teams.

Consistently developing a strategic view and planning ahead to maximize profits, a larger focus is also put on standard of service and presentation that meets and surpasses guests' needs and expectations. Other responsibilities managing budgets and financial plans; controlling expenditures; and dealing with customer complaints and comments.

Vilalara Thalassa and Spa Resort General Manager April 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)

Faro Area, Portugal

Four Seasons Hotels and Resorts Hotel Manager Four Seasons Hotel and Residences Denver September 2016 - Present (3 years 8 months)

Greater Denver Area

Four Seasons Resort and Residences Whistler Resort Manager

December 2013 - September 2016 (2 years 10 months)

British Columbia, Canada

Resort Manager of the Four Seasons Resort and residences in Whistler since November 2013 holding a senior managerial role with oversight of hotel operations.

The role oversees three major divisions, run by senior managers themselves: Rooms, Food & Beverage and Spa. The role oversees eight Department Heads, and twenty assistant managers/supervisory roles. Approximately 100 employees indirectly report to the Resort Manager.

As the operational leader, the Resort Manager is responsible for the day to day operations, long term resort service and operational strategies, flawless service execution and innovation. As the Resort manager I am also responsible for the health, safety and welfare of the hotel guests and employees.

Four Seasons Resort Maui at Wailea 6 years 10 months

Director of Rooms November 2010 - October 2013 (3 years) Maui, Hawaii

Responsible for 320 employees. Ares of responsibility involved rooms operations, front desk, concierge, housekeeping, laundry, guest services, PBX, reservations, Kids club, Pool and recreation. Responsible to set the strategic operational plan and capital budget for the entire division.

Director of Rooms
June 2008 - October 2010 (2 years 5 months)

Managed the Rooms Operations of 431 Rooms Golf and Private Club Resort in the Dallas Fort Worth Area

Page 2 of 4

Director of Rooms (Assistance) March 2008 - May 2008 (3 months)

Responsible for the Rooms division operations lead a team of 200 employees in a union environment

Assistant Director of Rooms
January 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 5 months)

Guest services, Concierge, PBX, Front Desk and Gift shop

Four Seasons Miami Director of Rooms (Assistance) November 2007 - February 2008 (4 months)

Rooms division task force,

Four Seasons Hotel Shanghai Front Office Manager May 2004 - November 2006 (2 years 7 months)

Front office responsibilities, Front desk, club floor, concierge, guest services

Lapa Palace Orient Express Hotel Director of Rooms August 2003 - May 2004 (10 months)

Managed the Rooms Operations of a 130 room Boutique Hotel in the Lisbon Area

Ritz Four Seasons Hotel Lisboa Assistant front Office Manager 2001 - 2003 (2 years)

Front desk and Guest services

Four Seasons resort Sharm El Sheik Openning Assistant Housekeeping Manager May 2002 - July 2002 (3 months) Sharm El Sheik

Pre Opening and Opening of the first European Resort concept for Four Seasons Hotels. Worked directly with an international task force of 200 plus co workers.

Four Seasons Hotel Ritz Lisbon Front Desk Overnight Manager February 2001 - September 2001 (8 months) Front desk and Night audit responsibilities

Education

Universite Toulouse le Mirail Major in Economy, DEUG · (1996 - 1997)

Univeriste Toulouse UT1
Hotel Management, Economics · (1995 - 1997)

Escola Superior De Hotelaria e turismo do Estoril Bachelor, Hotel Management · (1992 - 1995)